A district attorney out for a conviction. A new lawyer out of
her league. A young boy who knew too much.
The Client is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Joel Schumacher.
A street-wise kid, Mark Sway, sees the suicide of Jerome Clifford, a prominent Louisiana
lawyer, whose current client is Barry 'The Blade' Muldano, a Mafia hit-man.
Before Jerome shoots himself, he tells Mark where
the body of a Senator is buried.
Clifford shoots himself and Mark is found at the scene, and both the FBI and the
Mafia quickly realize that Mark probably knows more than he says.
Mark Sway, played by Brad Renfro.
Reggie Love, played by Susan Sarandon.
Roy Foltrigg, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Dianne Sway, played by Mary-Louise Parker.
Barry Muldano, played by Anthony LaPaglia.
Thomas Fink, played by Bradley Whitford.
The Client is a 1994 American legal thriller film directed by Joel Schumacher, and starring Susan Sarandon, Tommy Lee Jones,
Mary-Louise Parker, Anthony LaPaglia, Anthony Edwards, Ossie Davis, and introducing Brad Renfro in his film debut.
It is based on the 1993 novel by John Grisham.
It was filmed in Memphis, Tennessee.
The Client was theatrically released in the United States by Warner Bros.
on July 20, 1994, and was a box-office hit, grossing
$117.6 million against a $45 million budget.
It received positive reviews from critics, with the performances of
Sarandon, Jones and Renfro in particular earning high praise.
The film explores themes of suicide, sibling
relationship, brother, gangster, investigation.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.